Yumi's Cells 2
유미의 세포들 2
Episode 21 Ba Bi's Secret
21화 바비의 비밀
Nice to meet you. I'm Team Leader Yu Ba Bi.
만나서 반가워요. 저는 팀장 유바비 입니다.
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
- 안녕하세요. - 만나서 반가워요.
- Nice to meet you. Let's all work well together. - Hello.
- 만나서 반가워요. 모두 함께 잘 일합시다. - 안녕하세요.
All right, let's have some welcome applause.
좋아요, 환영 박수를 보내주세요.
It would be nice to eat lunch together.
점심 같이 먹으면 좋을 것 같아요.
Yes, Team Leader. I've made a reservation at a restaurant.
네, 팀 리더님. 나는 레스토랑을 예약했어요.
- Should we take off in five minutes? - Sounds good.
- 5분 후에 이륙할까요? - 좋은 것 같아요.
- Then I'll see you all in five minutes. - All right.
- 그럼 5분 후에 모두 뵙겠습니다. - 괜찮은.
I didn't realize during the interview,
인터뷰 중에는 몰랐어요
but Team Leader is super handsome. HGW*. (Handsomest Guy in the World)
그런데 팀장이 정말 잘생겼어요. HGW*. (세상에서 가장 잘생긴 남자)
There is something you've got to do when you see a HGW.
HGW를 보면 꼭 해야 할 일이 있습니다.
My team leader is a HGW.
우리 팀 리더는 HGW입니다.
- A HGW? - The first one looks good. But…
- HGW요? - 첫 번째는 괜찮은 것 같습니다. 하지만…
But he's got more charming features, too many to just confine him to the term HGW.
그러나 그는 HGW라는 용어에만 국한하기에는 너무 많은 매력적인 기능을 가지고 있습니다.
This, this, and this.
이것, 이것, 그리고 이것.
He's so passionate.
그는 정말 열정적이에요.
It would be nice if we lowered the colors.
색상을 낮추면 좋을 것 같습니다.
He looks sexy when he's concentrating
집중하고 있는 모습이 섹시해 보여
on something
뭔가
Daehan Noodles Jeju Branch
대한면 제주지사
I admit. It's not enough to just describe this guy as HGW.
나는 인정한다. 이 사람을 HGW라고 표현하는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
Gosh! I'm sorry. Sorry.
이런! 죄송합니다. 죄송합니다.
No. HGW plus sexy.
아니요. HGW 플러스 섹시.
Team Leader's unexpected charm
팀장의 의외의 매력
doesn't end there.
거기서 끝나지 않습니다.
Who sent the fax to Good Food? I told an intern to do it earlier.
누가 Good Food에 팩스를 보냈나요? 인턴한테 좀 더 일찍 하라고 했어요.
That was me.
그게 바로 나였어.
- Do you know that you sent the headquarters' contract to a different company? - Really?
- 본사 계약서를 다른 회사에 보낸 거 아시나요? - 정말?
Even the competitor's contract price has been passed on.
심지어 경쟁사의 계약 가격도 전가되었습니다.
Do you think you're still in school? Get it together.
아직 학교에 있다고 생각하시나요? 함께 해보세요.
- I'm sorry. - We'll talk about it later.
- 죄송합니다. - 나중에 얘기하자.
This is crazy! He's so charismatic.
이건 미친 짓이야! 그는 정말 카리스마가 넘치네요.
HGW. Sexy. Charisma.
HGW. 섹시한. 카리스마.
He's been pouring out three charming features in just a few days.
그는 불과 며칠 사이에 세 가지 매력적인 기능을 쏟아내고 있다.
He's hit the grand slam in the shortest time.
그는 최단 시간에 그랜드슬램을 달성했다.
Yu Ba Bi
유바비
Suddenly my heart started pounding like crazy and my blood circulation got faster.
갑자기 심장이 미친 듯이 뛰기 시작했고 혈액순환이 빨라졌습니다.
I ultimately without doubt started liking Team Leader.
나는 궁극적으로 의심 할 여지없이 팀 리더를 좋아하기 시작했습니다.
I'll be back.
나는 돌아올 것이다.
Furthermore, we even
게다가 우리는
live in the same neighborhood.
같은 동네에 살아요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Wow. Do you live here? I live here, too.
우와. 당신은 여기에 살고 있습니까? 나도 여기에 산다.
I'm sorry but who…?
미안하지만 누구...?
Oh, I'm… I'm the newly hired student intern.
아, 저는... 새로 입사한 학생 인턴이에요.
Ah, that's right. It was Yu …
아, 그렇군요. 유였습니다...
I'm Yu Da Eun. Hello.
저는 유다은이에요. 안녕하세요.
That's right. Miss Yu Da Eun. You live in this neighborhood?
좋아요. 유다은 선생님. 이 동네에 살아요?
Yes. That tangerine orchard is my house.
예. 그 감귤 과수원이 내 집이야.
I see.
알겠어요.
- Are you on your way to work? - Yes, you too?
- 출근 중이신가요? - 네, 당신도요?
Yes. I'm still so nervous.
예. 아직도 너무 긴장돼요.
No need. You should relax.
필요하지 않습니다. 긴장을 풀어야합니다.
I will. Thank you.
그럴게요. 감사합니다.
Then I'll see you at work.
그럼 직장에서 뵙겠습니다.
All right.
괜찮은.
I think this must be fate.
이건 운명이 아닐까 싶습니다.
What to do? My heart feels as if it's going to explode.
무엇을 해야 할까요? 가슴이 터질 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
Person who falls in love easily! Good morning! It's about time you tell the Team Leader you like him.
쉽게 사랑에 빠지는 사람! 좋은 아침이에요! 이제 팀 리더에게 당신이 그를 좋아한다고 말할 시간입니다.
If you've held it in while you found three charming qualities, then you've held it in well.
세 가지 매력적인 특성을 발견하는 동안 그것을 참아왔다면, 당신은 그것을 잘 참아낸 것입니다.
Acknowledge it.
그것을 인정하십시오.
Acknowledged. Acknowledged no matter what.
확인되었습니다. 상관없이 인정합니다.
- Excuse me. - I acknowledge–
- 실례합니다. - 인정합니다–
How do you get to work from here?
여기서 회사까지 어떻게 가나요?
I transfer the bus twice.
버스를 두 번 갈아탔어요.
- Get in. - Sorry?
- 들어가세요. - 죄송해요?
It's cold. Get in. Let's go together.
춥다. 타세요. 같이 가자.
OMG. Was 'get in' always this sweet?
어머나. '들어가다'가 원래 이렇게 달콤했나요?
That was the sweetest ever.
그것은 지금까지 가장 달콤했습니다.
So how's work? Is it doable?
그럼 일은 어때요? 그것은 가능합니까?
Yes.
예.
We just make you make copies and send faxes. There's less than you thought, right?
우리는 당신에게 복사를 하고 팩스를 보내면 됩니다. 생각보다 양이 적죠?
No, it's fun.
아니요, 재미있어요.
I'm glad it's fun.
재미있다니 기쁘네요.
But when I found his fourth charm,
하지만 그의 네 번째 매력을 발견했을 때,
weirdly my heart just settled down.
이상하게도 마음이 안정됐어요.
No, I didn't tell him. Team Leader was that.
아니, 난 그에게 말하지 않았어요. 팀 리더가 그랬다.
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
Do you know what people like Team Leader is called?
팀리더 같은 사람을 뭐라고 부르는지 아시나요?
Neomsabyeok*. (someone so perfect that he's unattainable)
넘사벽*. (너무 완벽해서 도달할 수 없는 사람)
Yumi: Ba Bi, good morning!
유미: 바비, 좋은 아침이에요!
You meet them maybe once if you're lucky.
운이 좋으면 한 번쯤 만날 수도 있습니다.
And anyway they already have girlfriends.
그리고 어쨌든 그들은 이미 여자 친구가 있습니다.
Thank you for the ride.
태워주셔서 감사합니다.
You go ahead. I need to make a call.
계속하세요. 전화를 해야 해요.
Yes, sure.
네, 그렇죠.
Have a good day.
좋은 하루 보내세요.
Yumi, did you sleep well?
유미 씨, 잘 잤어요?
I had a beer before going to bed.
잠들기 전에 맥주를 마셨습니다.
He's someone who'd not be with me even if he didn't have a girlfriend.
여자친구가 없어도 나와 함께하지 않을 사람이다.
That's what a neomsabyeok is.
그것이 바로 범사벽이다.
Marketing Department Team 1 Yu Ba Bi
마케팅1팀 유바비
Still, it's okay because I'm someone who falls in love easily.
그래도 난 사랑에 쉽게 빠지는 사람이니까 괜찮아.
I'll find someone else in a few days anyway.
어차피 며칠 안에 다른 사람을 찾을 거예요.
It's so nice out.
밖이 너무 좋아요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
- We meet again. - Hello.
- 우리 또 만나요. - 안녕하세요.
I'm here to get a coffee too.
나도 커피 한잔 마시러 왔어요.
I'm here to study.
나는 공부하러 왔습니다.
- Do you want something else to drink? - No, I'm all right.
- 다른 것도 마시고 싶나요? - 아니, 난 괜찮아.
- Then how about a cookie? - It's all right.
- 그럼 쿠키는 어때요? - 괜찮아요.
Good, then.
그럼 좋아요.
Could I have one cappuccino,
카푸치노 한 잔만 주시겠어요
Yes.
예.
and one of everything here, please.
여기 있는 것 중 하나를 주세요.
- Eat some while you study. - Thank you.
- 공부하면서 좀 먹어라. - 감사합니다.
By the way, you're so cool.
그건 그렇고, 당신은 정말 멋지다.
- I am? - Yes. I heard you're a writer.
- 그래요? - 예. 당신이 작가라고 들었어요.
Not yet.
아직 아님.
I just got a proposal. Where did you hear that rumor from?
방금 제안을 받았어요. 그 소문은 어디서 들었나요?
Team Leader bragged about you a lot.
팀장님이 당신 자랑을 많이 하셨습니다.
- Really? - Yes.
- 정말? - 예.
So I was always curious what kind of a person you might be.
그래서 나는 당신이 어떤 사람일지 항상 궁금했어요.
I didn't know that Ba Bi would brag about me that much.
바비가 저를 그렇게 자랑할 줄은 몰랐어요.
Everyone at work knows that the Team Leader met his girlfriend
직장의 모든 사람들은 팀 리더가 여자친구를 만났다는 것을 알고 있습니다
at the headquarters.
본사에서.
I see.
알겠어요.
Don't you have a boyfriend?
남자친구 없어요?
Not yet.
아직 아님.
Actually I've never dated anyone yet.
사실 저는 아직 누구와도 데이트를 해본 적이 없습니다.
Really? You're so pretty though.
정말? 그래도 당신은 너무 예뻐요.
You two look good together.
둘이 사이가 좋아 보이는군요.
I want to have an office romance like that when I get a job later.
나중에 취업하면 그런 오피스 로맨스를 하고 싶다.
She's still so young. She's a kid.
그녀는 아직 너무 어려요. 그녀는 어린 아이입니다.
She's so cute.
그녀는 너무 귀여워요.
Why were we so nervous about going against a kid like that?
그런 꼬마를 상대하는 것에 우리는 왜 그렇게 긴장했나요?
I told you, right? That we don't have to worry.
내가 말했지, 그렇지? 우리는 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
I think we said something unnecessary yesterday. It was unnecessary.
어제 우리가 불필요한 말을 한 것 같아요. 불필요했습니다.
I have a question.
질문이 있습니다.
When did you start liking me?
언제부터 나를 좋아하기 시작했어요?
I asked when did you start liking me?
언제부터 나를 좋아하게 됐냐고 물었지?
Why are you suddenly asking that? It's out of the blue.
갑자기 그걸 왜 묻는거야? 갑작스러운 일입니다.
Because I was curious, all of a sudden.
갑자기 궁금해졌으니까요.
That was probably ...
아마도...
Hold on, I keep all the memories
잠깐만요, 난 모든 추억을 간직하고 있어요
related to love.
사랑과 관련.
If you ask when he first started to like Yumi ...
언제부터 유미를 좋아하게 됐냐고 묻는다면...
Oh, yes! That's right!
아, 그렇죠! 좋아요!
He first started to like Yumi when—
그가 처음으로 Yumi를 좋아하기 시작한 때는—
Unconscious Zone Danger! No entry
무의식지대 위험! 입장 불가
Did you bring it?
가져왔어?
Here. Love's trying to tell her everything, like an idiot.
여기. 사랑은 바보처럼 그녀에게 모든 것을 말하려고 합니다.
I took it right before he did.
나는 그가 그러기 직전에 그것을 가져갔다.
Good job. He's way too naive.
잘했어요. 그 사람은 너무 순진해요.
Why would Yumi be asking that question now?
유미가 지금 왜 그런 질문을 하는 걸까요?
Right after he said that he'd given his jacket for Da Eun to use.
다은이에게 재킷을 주었다고 말한 직후였다.
You get where I'm going, right?
내가 가는 곳으로 갈 수 있지, 그렇지?
Yes, I've got an idea.
네, 좋은 생각이 있어요.
It's better
더 좋아
to get rid of unnecessary memories.
불필요한 기억을 없애기 위해.
That was probably ...
아마도...
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
You're not sure?
확실하지 않나요?
I don't really remember.
나는 정말로 기억하지 못한다.
How can you not remember that?
어떻게 그걸 기억하지 못해요?
I don't know exactly when it was.
정확히 언제였는지 모르겠어요.
At some point, I just started to care about a woman named Kim Yumi.
어느 순간부터 김유미라는 여자에게 관심이 생기기 시작했다.
I probably was ...
아마...
P.Y.
P.Y.
I was permeated by Yumi.
나에게는 유미가 스며들었다.
I'm being serious right now.
나 지금 진지하게 말하는 중이야.
I really don't remember.
정말 기억이 안 나네요.
I was permeated by you.
나는 당신에 의해 스며 들었다.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Why did I faint?
내가 왜 기절했나요?
I was definitely about to answer the question about when I first started liking Yumi ...
유미를 처음 좋아하게 된 계기에 대한 질문에 꼭 답을 하려고 했는데...
Huh? Ah, that's right.
뭐? 아, 그렇군요.
I remember.
나는 기억한다.
That's right. It was then.
좋아요. 그때였습니다.
Really?
정말?
I was dancing?
내가 춤을 추고 있었나요?
Yeah, a little.
응, 조금.
Your shoulder dance was cute.
어깨춤이 귀여웠어요.
Oh, my. I don't remember that at all.
아, 이런. 나는 그것을 전혀 기억하지 못합니다.
I really did that?
내가 정말 그랬어?
My heart fluttered for the first time back then.
그때 처음으로 가슴이 뛰었다.
That was the first time my heart fluttered when I saw Yumi, and —
그때 처음으로 유미를 보고 마음이 설렜고, -
Is this right?
이게 맞나요?
Episode 22 Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong
22회 편집장 안대용
14 years ago
14년 전
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
- I'm hungry. - Me too.
- 배고파요. - 저도요.
There was a freshman in the same liberal arts class as me.
나와 같은 교양과목을 듣는 신입생이 있었다.
I want a giant pork cutlet.
나는 거대한 돈까스를 원한다.
What a surprise.
놀랐는 걸.
I wanted to get close to her.
나는 그녀에게 가까이 다가가고 싶었습니다.
No.
아니요.
I just wanted to be able to exchange greetings with her.
나는 단지 그녀와 인사를 나누고 싶었습니다.
So I gathered up my courage, but...
그래서 용기를 냈지만...
That's what I'm saying. That's—
그것이 내가 말하는 것입니다. 그건—
Do you ... Hi! You know me, right?
당신은 ... 안녕하세요! 저 아시죠?
That's what I was going to say.
그것이 내가 말하려고 했던 것입니다.
But... Do you ...
하지만... 당신은 ...
know me?
나를 알아?
Love Error:
사랑 오류:
A type of language error that only occurs
A type of language error that only occurs
in front of the person that you like.
만 발생하는 언어 오류 유형
Were you talking to me just now?
좋아하는 사람 앞에서.
Well... Do you know him?
지금 나한테 얘기 중이었어?
Aren't you crazy?!
음... 혹시 그 사람 알아요?
It's not like you were trying to pick a fight with her! What was that?
미친거 아냐?!
Man, that was so embarrassing.
당신이 그녀와 싸움을 하려고 했던 것 같지는 않아요! 그게 뭐였지?
However,
정말 당황스러웠어요.
they say that a crisis is an opportunity. The Magic Mountain, by Thomas Man
위기는 기회라고 하잖아요. 마법의 산, 토마스 맨
How much is this?
이것은 얼마입니까?
- That day, - It's 35,000 won  (≈ $27).
- 그날, - 35,000원입니다.
I bought a book that wasn't related to my major, for the first time since I entered graduate school.
대학원에 입학한 이후 처음으로 전공과 관련 없는 책을 샀습니다.
The problem was that the book was extremely boring.
문제는 그 책이 너무 지루하다는 것이었다.
I couldn't get through it no matter how hard I tried.
아무리 노력해도 극복할 수 없었어요.
I needed to quickly read this, so I could talk to her at least once.
빨리 읽어서 그녀와 한 번이라도 이야기를 나눌 수 있어야 했어요.
She was already halfway through her copy of The Magic Mountain,
그녀는 이미 The Magic Mountain 사본을 절반쯤 읽었습니다.
but I was still on page 23.
하지만 아직 23페이지에 있었어요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Will I at least be able to introduce myself to her?
최소한 그녀에게 내 소개를 할 수 있을까요?
When I think of someone that I've met in my life who bewildered me, I can only think of one person.
살면서 만난 사람 중에 나를 당황하게 했던 사람을 생각하면 딱 한 사람밖에 떠오르지 않는다.
Who is it?
누구입니까?
When I was in my freshman year of college,
내가 대학교 1학년이었을 때,
there was some man who looked as if he was my seonbae by several years.
몇 년이 지나도 내 선배처럼 보이는 남자가 있었어요.
He suddenly came up and asked me something like, "Have you finished reading The Magic Mountain?"
갑자기 다가와서 "마법의 산(The Magic Mountain)을 다 읽었나요?" 같은 질문을 하더군요.
- Was he in the same major? - No, I didn't even know his name.
- 같은 전공이었나요? - 아니, 이름도 몰랐어요.
- He was probably in a different major, right? - Yeah.
- 아마 다른 전공이었겠죠? - 응.
I was so bewildered that I asked him why.
나는 너무 당황해서 그에게 이유를 물었다.
He just smirked and said, "I finished it."
그는 그냥 웃으며 "끝냈어요"라고 말했습니다.
Then he left.
그런 다음 그는 떠났습니다.
- That was it? - That was it.
- 그게 다야? - 그게 다야.
It's ridiculous, isn't it?
말도 안 되는 일이지, 그렇지?
He must have liked you.
그 사람이 당신을 좋아했나 봐요.
Why do you think that?
왜 그렇게 생각하세요?
Men know how other men think.
남자들은 다른 남자들이 어떻게 생각하는지 압니다.
Didn't he just want to talk to you about anything because he liked you?
그 사람은 그냥 당신이 좋아서 아무 얘기나 하고 싶었던 거 아니었나요?
I thought that too, but he went to the army right after that.
저도 그렇게 생각했는데 그 사람이 바로 군대에 갔거든요.
I have a feeling that that seonbae hadn't ever dated then.
그때 그 선배는 연애를 해본 적이 없었던 것 같아요.
No way! I told you, he was way older than me!
안 돼요! 내가 말했잖아, 그 사람은 나보다 훨씬 나이가 많아!
My heart hurts for some reason.
왠지 마음이 아프네요.
I wonder what he's doing now.
그 사람 지금 뭐하고 있는지 궁금해요.
I'll head straight in. I feel like I'll be late.
바로 들어갈게요. 늦을 것 같아요.
- You said your meeting at the publishing company is at three, right? - Yes.
- 출판사 미팅이 3시라고 했죠? - 예.
Call me afterward and tell me how it went.
나중에 나한테 전화해서 어떻게 됐는지 말해줘.
All right. Bye!
괜찮은. 안녕!
Be careful on your way back!
돌아가는 길 조심하세요!
Rice with fish roe, cold buckwheat noodles, or the menu set.
명란밥, 냉메밀국수, 메뉴세트.
Rice with fish roe, cold buckwheat noodles, or the m-menu set.
명란밥, 냉메밀국수, M메뉴 세트.
So he's stuck here again.
그래서 그는 또 여기에 갇혔습니다.
This is always difficult even though I try to solve it every day.
매일 풀려고 노력해도 항상 어려운 문제입니다.
On top of that, I always get stuck at the very end.
게다가 맨 마지막에 항상 막히는 편이에요.
Man, seriously! Today's lunch menu: Army stew, Big Pork Cutlet, Stir-Fried Pork Rice...
정말로요! 오늘 점심메뉴 : 군만두, 돈까스, 돼지고기볶음밥...
It's between rice with fish roe and cold buckwheat noodles.
생선알밥과 냉메밀국수 사이에 있어요.
No matter how much I look at it, both of these look like the right answer.
아무리 봐도 둘 다 정답인 것 같네요.
Man, I'm going to go crazy!
아저씨, 미칠 것 같아요!
Rice with fish roe, cold buckwheat noodles, or the menu set.
명란밥, 냉메밀국수, 메뉴세트.
Rice with fish roe, or cold buckwheat noodles?
어란밥인가, 아니면 냉메밀국수인가?
Yes?
예?
Editor-in-Chief, let's go.
편집장님, 가세요.
Hold on, hold on.
잠깐만요, 잠깐만요.
- I still haven't decided yet. - Pardon?
- 아직 결정하지 못했어요. - 뭐라고요?
- We're late, though. We have to leave right— - Wait a second.
- 하지만 우리는 늦었어요. 우리는 바로 떠나야 해— - 잠깐만요.
I think that rice with fish roe sounds good.
생선알을 넣은 밥이 좋을 것 같아요.
What do you think, Mi Yeon? Do you like cold buckwheat noodles more?
미연 씨는 어떻게 생각해요? 여러분은 냉메밀면을 더 좋아하시나요?
Editor-in-Chief. Your lunch today is going to be a sandwich or pasta anyway.
편집장. 어쨌든 오늘 점심은 샌드위치나 파스타가 될 거예요.
- What are you pondering about? - What? According to whom?
- 무엇을 고민하고 있나요? - 무엇? 누구에 따르면?
You made a lunch appointment to meet with the new writer at the book café today.
당신은 오늘 북카페에서 신인 작가를 만나기 위해 점심 약속을 했습니다.
The cheesecake here is always delicious.
여기 치즈케이크는 언제나 맛있어요.
It's somewhat of a small consolation.
조금이나마 작은 위로가 됩니다.
The writer said that she arrived.
작가가 도착했다고 했어요.
The taxi driver must have gotten a little lost because he couldn't find the café. I'll go bring her in.
택시기사는 카페를 찾지 못해 조금 헤매었나 봅니다. 내가 가서 그녀를 데려올게.
- Are you Writer Kim? - Yes.
- 김 작가이신가요? - 예.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Editor-in-Chief, Writer Kim is here.
편집장 김작가가 왔습니다.
I'm Kim Yumi.
저는 김유미예요.
Do you believe in fate?
당신은 운명을 믿나요?
- No, not at all. - I didn't believe in it either.
- 아니요, 전혀요. -나도 안 믿었어요.
At least not until I ended up meeting her again.
적어도 내가 그녀를 다시 만날 때까지는 그렇지 않았습니다.
Can you believe this situation?
이 상황을 믿을 수 있나요?
The last new writer that I picked
내가 선택한 마지막 신인 작가
is none other than her!
다름 아닌 그녀야!
It's possible that this was fate from the beginning.
어쩌면 처음부터 운명이었을지도 모른다.
It's kind of salty but it tastes pretty good.
좀 짠 편인데 맛이 꽤 괜찮네요.
Stuff your face quietly!
조용히 얼굴을 꽉 채우세요!
Can you stuff cake down your throat at such a historic moment?
이런 역사적인 순간에 케이크를 목구멍에 집어넣을 수 있나요?
- Go and bring BGM* (background music)  cell here right now! - All right, all right!
- 지금 바로 BGM*(배경음악) 셀을 여기로 가져오세요! - 알았어, 알았어!
He should have done it himself. Why is he making me do it? I'm only going today.
그 사람이 직접 했어야 했어요. 그 사람은 왜 나한테 그런 짓을 하게 만드는 걸까? 오늘만 갈 예정이에요.
This is the most, most important moment in Dae Yong's life!
대용의 인생에서 가장, 가장 중요한 순간입니다!
Huh?
뭐?
Play some background music that suits this destined situation.
이 운명적인 상황에 어울리는 배경 음악을 재생해 보세요.
- Right now! - Yes, sir!
- 지금 바로! - 네, 선생님!
[3, 2, 1]
[3, 2, 1]
- ♪ I knew it.
- ♪ 그럴 줄 알았어.
That's it!
그게 다야!
- That's it! Good! ♪ Even if you can't remember me
- 그게 다야! 좋은! ♪ 나를 기억하지 못하더라도
♪ I remember you.
♪ 나는 당신을 기억합니다.
♪ The fated destiny
♪ 운명적인 운명
♪ connecting you and me.
♪당신과 나를 연결합니다.
Bravo!
브라보!
That was perfect background music. Bravo!
완벽한 배경음악이었습니다. 브라보!
It's nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong* (dae = great/large, yong = dragon)
편집장 안대용* (대 = 크다/큰, 용 = 용)
I'm Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong.
편집장 안대용 입니다.
Yes, hello, Mr. Editor-in-Chief. I'm Kim Yumi.
네, 안녕하세요, 편집장 님. 저는 김유미예요.
Thank you so much for getting in contact with me.
저에게 연락해주셔서 정말 감사드립니다.
- I really never even imagined this, but— - Have a seat.
- 이건 정말 상상도 못했는데... - 자리에 앉으세요.
You said that you first thought of quitting your job and becoming a writer here?
처음에는 직장을 그만두고 여기서 작가가 되고 싶다는 생각을 했다고 했죠?
Yes.
예.
I did, so it feels a bit strange since you said that we should meet here.
그랬는데, 여기서 만나자고 하니까 좀 이상하네요.
You and our publishing company have a great connection.
당신과 우리 출판사는 좋은 관계를 갖고 있습니다.
- One moment. - Sure.
- 잠시만요. - 확신하는.
Yes?
예?
Are you not going to eat? It's delicious.
밥 안 먹을 거야? 맛있어요.
Please enjoy. I'm not really hungry.
즐겨주세요. 별로 배가 고프지 않아요.
I'm thankful to the Editor-in-Chief, but he seems to be really cold.
편집장님께 감사한데 정말 냉정하신 것 같아요.
- He doesn't talk much either. - Man, I'm not good with that kind of person.
- 그 사람도 말을 별로 안 해요. - 야, 나 그런 사람이랑 안 친해.
Yumi. Kim Yumi.
유미. 김유미.
So her name was Kim Yumi.
그래서 이름이 김유미였죠.
I was only able to find it out today.
오늘에서야 알 수 있었습니다.
Your name is beautiful, Miss Yu Mi.
이름이 참 아름답네요, 유미씨.
Kim Yu M—
김유엠—
I'll engrave it so that we'll never forget it.
잊지 않도록 새겨드리겠습니다.
Hey, Love!
안녕, 사랑!
Don't you see that I'm busy?
내가 바쁜 거 안보여?
You idiot! Yumi is calling us right now!
바보야! 지금 유미가 전화하고 있어요!
What?
무엇?
Excuse me, Editor-in-Chief.
죄송합니다, 편집장님.
Editor-in-Chief?
편집장?
Yes?
예?
If there's anything you want to know, please ask.
알고 싶은 것이 있으면 물어보세요.
Then are you the one
그렇다면 당신이 그 사람인가요
who will be in charge of my writing?
내 글은 누가 담당할 것인가?
No, I'm going to be the one in charge of you because he's busy.
아니요, 그 사람 바쁘기 때문에 제가 당신을 책임질 거예요.
Oh, I see.
알겠어요.
What a relief! We're not going to be stuck with the Editor-in-Chief!
정말 다행이네요! 우리는 편집장에게 얽매이지 않을 것입니다!
Our good luck just keeps flowing in!
우리의 행운이 계속 흘러들어오고 있어요!
You've got a lot of work on your plate right now, Miss Mi Yeon.
미연씨 지금 할 일이 너무 많아요.
I'll take over this one, since it's one that I picked out anyway.
어차피 내가 고른 거니까 이건 내가 맡을게.
But you have a very full schedule.
하지만 당신은 매우 빡빡한 일정을 가지고 있습니다.
I'll just have to put up with it,
그냥 참아야겠어,
since Writer Kim Yumi's success is also my responsibility.
김유미 작가의 성공도 내 몫이니까.
Yes...
네...
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Thank you for the ride.
태워주셔서 감사합니다.
Excuse me, Mr. Editor-in-Chief? When should I have the editing done by?
죄송합니다, 편집장 씨? 편집은 언제까지 완료해야 합니까?
Send it to me by Monday and come to see me at the publishing company on Tuesday.
월요일까지 보내주시고 화요일에 출판사로 만나러 오세요.
- Pardon? - What?! Monday? But today's Friday!
- 뭐라고요? - 무엇?! 월요일? 그런데 오늘은 금요일!
Then we're going to have to work on it over the weekend.
그럼 주말에 작업해야겠습니다.
What's our weekend schedule?
우리 주말 일정이 어떻게 되나요?
We planned to meet with Yi Da and Ruby to watch a movie and have a hot pot restaurant tour on Saturday.
토요일에는 이다와 루비를 만나 영화도 보고 훠궈 맛집 투어도 하기로 했어요.
Sunday is Seong Mi's wedding. We're booked for the weekend.
일요일은 성미씨의 결혼식이에요. 우리는 주말에 예약이 꽉 차 있어요.
Ask him to adjust the time!
시간을 조정해달라고 요청하세요!
We already have previous engagements, so what can we do?!
이미 이전 계약이 있는데 어떻게 해야 할까요?!
- I ... - Won't that be too tough for her?
- 나는 ... - 그 사람한테는 너무 힘들지 않을까요?
Yes. I think the work schedule is a little tight...
예. 근무 일정이 좀 빡빡한 것 같아요...
We have to match the publishing schedule, so there's nothing we can do about it.
출판 일정을 맞춰야 해서 저희가 할 수 있는 게 없어요.
I understand.
이해합니다.
He said he can't.
그는 할 수 없다고 말했습니다.
Why are you agreeing so quickly?
왜 그렇게 빨리 동의하는 거야?
I'm scared of the Editor-in-Chief.
편집장 무서워요.
- All right, I understand. - Good.
- 알았어, 이해해. - 좋은.
You can send it to the email address on my business card.
내 명함에 기재된 이메일 주소로 보내주시면 됩니다.
- All right. - Let's go.
- 괜찮은. - 갑시다.
Will she be able to finish it in a few days? She's a total rookie.
그녀는 며칠 안에 그 일을 끝낼 수 있을까요? 그녀는 완전 신인이에요.
Whether she's a rookie or not, she's a writer now.
신인이건 아니건 그녀는 이제 작가다.
It's something a writer has to do.
작가가 해야 할 일이죠.
You said she's your fated woman, so why are you being so cold toward her?
그 사람이 네 운명의 여자라고 했는데 왜 그 사람한테 그렇게 차갑게 굴어?
Hey, can't you talk to her in a kind way?
저기, 그 사람한테 좀 친절하게 얘기 좀 해주실 수 없나요?
What have you been accumulating since earlier?
아까부터 무엇을 쌓아왔나요?
I'm accumulating all the kindness together.
친절함을 모두 함께 쌓아가고 있어요.
Wait, you should have used some of it on Yumi since you have so much.
잠깐만요, 당신은 그것을 너무 많이 가지고 있기 때문에 Yumi에게 그것의 일부를 사용했어야 했습니다.
I don't want to. I'm going to save it and then use it all at once.
나는 원하지 않는다. 저장했다가 한번에 다 써봐야겠네요.
If you save it too much, it'll go to waste, you jerk!
너무 아껴두면 낭비야, 이 멍청아!
Have you guys already forgotten what happened in the past?
여러분, 지난 일을 벌써 잊으셨나요?
After 364 days of being so sweet, that he was dripping with honey,
꿀이 뚝뚝 떨어질 정도로 달콤한 364일을 보낸 후,
he got angry just once ...
그는 딱 한번 화를 냈어요 ...
- Wait, I— - I'm disappointed in you, seriously!
- 잠깐만요, 저는— - 정말 실망했어요!
J-Ji Hye! Ji-Ji Hye!
지혜! 지지혜!
That's what happened. I felt so wronged!
그것이 일어난 일입니다. 나는 너무 잘못 느꼈다!
But if I do the opposite and treat her harshly for 364 days
하지만 내가 반대로 364일 동안 그녀를 가혹하게 대하면
and then show her affection just once, what do you think will happen?
그리고 한번만 애정을 표현하면 어떻게 될 것 같나요?
She'll think, "Oh, so he had this kind of side to him too."
'아, 그 사람에게도 이런 면이 있었구나'라고 생각하게 될 거예요.
Don't you think?
그렇게 생각하지 않나요?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
That's why I'm accumulating it.
그렇기 때문에 쌓아두는 중이에요.
I'll gather a ton of kindness together and use it all at once!
천만다행의 친절을 모아서 한번에 사용하겠습니다!
Love is being strategic!
사랑은 전략적이다!
I have to stay up all night from now on. There's a ton of stuff I have to edit.
이제부터 밤새도록 깨어 있어야 해요. 편집해야 할 내용이 너무 많아요.
- How is the Editor-in-Chief? - The Editor-in-Chief?
- 편집장은 어떤가요? - 편집장요?
If I put it nicely, he's a professional.
좋게 말하면 그 사람은 프로예요.
If I put it badly, he's totally cold–
나쁘게 말하면 그 사람은 완전 차가워요.
Cold? Cold-blooded? Poisonous snake?
추운? 냉혈? 독이 있는 뱀?
Never mind. I don't want to badmouth him.
괜찮아요. 나는 그를 욕하고 싶지 않습니다.
Either way, he's the person who picked my story. So I don't want to talk badly about him.
어쨌든 그 사람은 내 이야기를 고른 사람이야. 그래서 나는 그에 대해 나쁘게 말하고 싶지 않습니다.
Although it looks like I'll be pulling all-nighters for the next three days,
앞으로 3일 동안 밤을 새워야 할 것 같지만,
I'm not going to badmouth him.
나는 그를 욕하지 않을 것입니다.
Aigoo. My Kim Yumi's good times have all ended.
아이구. 우리 김유미의 즐거운 시간은 모두 끝났습니다.
I'm serious. I'll have to cancel all my weekend plans.
나는 진지하다. 주말 계획을 모두 취소해야겠어요.
Even if I do go to my friend's wedding, I think I'll have to just take pictures with her and then come back.
친구 결혼식에 가더라도 그냥 사진만 찍고 다시 와야 할 것 같아요.
By the way, the Editor-in-Chief seems familiar.
그런데 편집장은 낯익은 것 같습니다.
- Is he famous? - I looked him up, but he's not.
- 그 사람 유명해요? - 그 사람을 찾아봤는데 그렇지 않네요.
But I feel like I've seen him somewhere.
하지만 어딘가에서 본 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
Where did I see him?
내가 그를 어디서 봤나요?
To put it in one word, chapter five is a mess.
한 마디로 말하면 5장은 엉망이다.
Chapter six is so boring that I dozed off while I was reading it.
6장은 너무 지루해서 읽다가 졸았어요.
Rewrite chapter seven as well. A love triangle
7장도 다시 쓰세요. 삼각관계
The male lead's mindset is so childish that it made me wonder if there was a man like him in the entire world.
세상에 이런 남자가 있을까 싶을 정도로 남자주인공의 사고방식은 너무 유치하다.
It's unrealistic.
그것은 비현실적입니다.
As for chapter eight... just get rid of it and rewrite the whole thing.
8장에 관해서는... 그냥 없애고 전체를 다시 쓰세요.
On the contrary, the emotions are getting cut off more than the first draft.
오히려 초안보다 감정이 잘려나가는 것 같아요.
In short, it got worse. You changed the angle of the story.
한마디로 상황이 더 나빠졌습니다. 이야기의 각도를 바꾸셨습니다.
I didn't tell you to edit it for it to turn out like this.
이렇게 나오도록 편집하라고는 말하지 않았습니다.
Do it all over again.
다시 한번 해보세요.
All of it? Again?
전부요? 다시?
Yes.
예.
All of it.
모든 것.
Uh...
어...
He's so mean! Because you made the timeline so tight,
그 사람은 정말 못됐어! 일정을 너무 빡빡하게 설정하셨기 때문에
I can't even turn this well-functioning millstone properly because I'm in such a hurry!
이 잘 돌아가는 맷돌도 너무 서두르느라 제대로 돌릴 수가 없어요!
- Hey. - Let go!
- 여기요. - 놔!
Rampage, what's wrong with you?
램페이지, 무슨 일이야?
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
I've got to say what needs to be said! Hey, Editor-in-Chief!
해야 할 말은 해야지! 안녕하세요, 편집장님!
Starting now, listen to me carefully!
지금부터 내 말을 잘 들어보세요!
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
I understand. I'll edit it again.
이해합니다. 다시 편집하겠습니다.
Please hurry. There's not a lot of time.
서둘러주세요. 시간이 별로 없어요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Are you going to stay here and work on it today?
오늘 여기 남아서 일할 건가요?
No. I'm going to get my things together and work on it when I get home.
아니요. 집에 오면 물건을 정리해서 작업할 예정입니다.
I'm going to go home and eat. I also have to eat to live!
집에 가서 먹을 거예요. 나도 먹고 살아야지!
It's really late. Would you like to eat before you go?
정말 늦었어요. 가기 전에 밥이라도 먹고 갈래?
I had a late lunch, so I'm not really hungry.
점심을 늦게 먹어서 별로 배가 고프지 않네요.
That's a lie.
그건 거짓말이에요.
Ah, I see.
아, 그렇군요.
Even if she had a late lunch, wouldn't she be hungry at nine o'clock?
점심을 늦게 먹어도 9시가 되면 배가 고프지 않을까요?
You fool, she's saying that she's not comfortable eating with you. Don't you even know that?
바보야, 그 사람이 너랑 같이 식사하는 게 불편하다고 하잖아. 당신은 그것도 모르나요?
What? There's no way!
무엇? 방법이 없습니다!
She could have eaten lunch around six o'clock!
6시쯤 점심을 먹을 수도 있었을 텐데!
If she ate at that time, then isn't that dinner?
그 시간에 먹었다면 그게 저녁 아닌가요?
- It seems you ate a very late lunch. - Yes.
- 점심을 아주 늦게 먹은 것 같군요. - 예.
You said that you were saving up your kindness. What the hell is this situation?
당신은 친절을 아끼고 있다고 말했습니다. 도대체 이게 무슨 상황이지?
- Stop it! - This is all your fault!
- 그만해요! - 이건 다 네 잘못이야!
I understand.
이해합니다.
Don't forget your manuscript and finish up.
원고를 잊지 말고 마무리하세요.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
I seriously almost died of hunger.
정말 굶어 죽을 뻔했어요.
This is crazy. How am I supposed to write all of this by Friday?
이건 미친 짓이야. 금요일까지 이 모든 것을 어떻게 다 써야 하나요?
Today is Tuesday, if I write it by Friday,
오늘이 화요일인데 금요일까지 쓰면
I bet they're going to tell me to edit it over the weekend. It's so obvious.
주말에 편집하라고 할 것 같아요. 너무나 분명합니다.
I see how he works now. I think he's trying to screw with me, that bast—
나는 그가 지금 어떻게 일하는지 봅니다. 내 생각엔 그 사람이 나랑 장난하려고 하는 것 같아, 그 인피—
That bastard?
그 놈?
No, I don't want to go that far.
아니요, 그렇게까지 가고 싶지 않습니다.
Still, he is the savior who picked me.
그래도 그 사람이 나를 택한 구세주다.
- Should I not come up this weekend? - What are you saying?
- 이번 주말에는 나오지 말아야 할까요? - 무슨 말이에요?
Even if I go, I think I'll just get in your way.
내가 가더라도 방해만 될 것 같아.
All I have to do is edit it perfectly by Friday.
금요일까지 완벽하게 편집하면 됩니다.
As you said, you don't know if you'll have to edit it again.
말씀하신 대로 다시 편집해야 할지 모르겠습니다.
No, no, I said no. I'll be fine.
아니요, 아니요, 아니요라고 했습니다. 나는 괜찮을 것이다.
What's this again?
이건 또 뭐야?
What?
무엇?
Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong
안대용 편집장
Ba Bi, I'll call you back.
바비야, 내가 다시 전화할게.
O-okay.
아-알았어.
Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong
안대용 편집장
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Writer, it's me, Ahn Dae Yong.
작가님, 안대용입니다.
Yes?
예?
I'm calling because I changed my mind about some things.
몇 가지 사항에 대해 마음이 바뀌어서 전화드렸습니다.
I thought I should let you know before you start editing.
편집을 시작하기 전에 알려드려야겠다고 생각했어요.
I see. What else is it ...
알겠어요. 또 뭐야...
Do you have something to write this down?
이거 적어둘 게 있나요?
One second.
1초.
Yes, go ahead please.
네, 계속하세요.
Yes. Chapter 3 ...
예. 3장 ...
The background? Yes, yes.
배경? 예, 그렇습니다.
I think it'd be better to change the order of the chapters in the second half.
후반부에는 챕터 순서를 바꾸는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Then I need to change more than what you said before.
그러면 아까 말씀하신 것보다 더 많은 것을 바꿔야 해요.
That's right.
좋아요.
I called you because I thought you might have started working already
당신이 이미 일을 시작했을지도 모른다고 생각해서 전화했어요
and didn't want you to do it twice.
그리고 당신이 그것을 두 번하는 것을 원하지 않았습니다.
Yes.
예.
Then good luck, Writer.
그럼 행운을 빌어요, 작가님.
What? Are you ending the call like this?
무엇? 통화를 이대로 끝내는 건가요?
Writer Kim Yumi
작가 김유미
Did you get home safely earlier?
일찍 집에 무사히 도착하셨나요?
Have you eaten dinner? There's so many things you could say!
저녁은 먹었나요? 당신이 말할 수 있는 것이 너무 많습니다!
We had to gather so much courage to make this call.
우리는 이 전화를 하기 위해 너무나 많은 용기를 모아야 했습니다.
You could have asked a personal question.
개인적인 질문을 했을 수도 있습니다.
I was wondering what you are doing now? Or what dramas you are watching?!
지금 뭐하고 계시는지 궁금하네요? 아니면 어떤 드라마를 보고 계시나요?!
It doesn't really work to be sweet when you're supposed to be sweet.
달콤해야 할 때 달콤해지는 것은 실제로 효과가 없습니다.
It's only kind if it's done at the right time.
적절한 시기에 완료되어야만 친절합니다.
It only makes the other person feel uncomfortable if you do it too much.
너무 많이 하면 상대방이 불편해집니다.
So, when is his timing?
그렇다면 그의 타이밍은 언제인가?
The time to use his kindness
그의 친절함을 발휘할 시간
is right now.
바로 지금입니다.
CEO Big dragon Ahn ("Big dragon" is just a translation of his first name)
안빅드래곤 대표이사 ("Big Dragon"은 그의 이름을 번역한 것일 뿐입니다)
Did you call for me?
나한테 전화했어?
Miss Mi Yeon, could you run an errand for me, please?
미연씨, 심부름 좀 해주시겠어요?
I hate him. I hate the Editor-in-Chief!
나는 그를 싫어. 나는 편집장을 싫어한다!
You said you weren't going to badmouth him because he's your savior.
당신은 그가 당신의 구원자이기 때문에 그를 욕하지 않을 것이라고 말했습니다.
I'm not badmouthing him.
나는 그를 욕하는 것이 아닙니다.
I'm saying I hate him! Hate isn't a swear word.
난 그 사람이 싫어요! 증오는 욕이 아닙니다.
Who could that be? Who is it?
그 사람은 누구일까요? 누구입니까?
Delivery!
배달!
I didn't order delivery though?
그런데 배달주문을 안했는데?
Yai Doughnuts
야이 도넛
Who is it?
누구입니까?
It seems someone sent me donuts.
누군가 나에게 도넛을 보낸 것 같습니다.
I think they've sent it to the right house, but who could it be from? 1344-4 Baeseok-dong, Ilsan-dong-gu, Apt 403 Kim Yumi
제 생각엔 그 사람들이 그것을 올바른 집으로 보낸 것 같아요. 그런데 누구에게서 온 걸까요? 일산동구 배석동 1344-4 김유미아파트 403호
Huh?
뭐?
Writer, the Editor-in-Chief told me to send you some snacks because you are working so hard.
작가님, 편집장님께서 너무 고생 많으시니 간식 좀 보내달라고 하셨습니다.
I sent doughnuts to your house.
내가 너희 집으로 도넛을 보냈어.
I'm delivering a message from the Editor-in-Chief too. Hang in there!
편집장님의 메시지도 전해드립니다. 거기 참으세요!
It may be difficult because of the impractical schedule, but hang in there for the rest of the manuscript.
일정이 비현실적이어서 힘들 수도 있지만, 나머지 원고는 조금만 기다려주세요.
Ba Bi, look at this.
바비야, 이것 좀 봐.
- Who sent it? - The Editor-in-Chief.
- 누가 보냈나요? - 편집장.
Episode 23: Earthquake
에피소드 23: 지진
The day when the aurora appeared in the sky,
하늘에 오로라가 나타난 날,
An aurora. Wow.
오로라. 우와.
Hunch received a message from the future.
헌치는 미래로부터 메시지를 받았습니다.
Is this for real?
이게 진짜인가요?
Hello? Who...?
안녕하세요? WHO...?
- Hunch! - Reason!
- 직감! - 이유!
Is it true? That you received a message from the future?
사실인가요? 미래로부터 메시지를 받았다고?
Yes, I definitely received it.
네, 확실히 받았습니다.
You're saying that Yumi's going to succeed?
유미가 성공할 거라는 겁니까?
She's going to become someone special? You're serious, right?
그녀는 특별한 사람이 될 것인가? 진심이군요, 그렇죠?
And? What else?
그리고? 또 뭐야?
Huh? Why?
뭐? 왜?
Yumi succeeding as a writer is a good thing.
유미가 작가로 성공한 건 좋은 일이다.
Yeah, that's true.
네, 사실이에요.
But if it's good news why didn't you call the village, but called me in the middle of the night?
그런데 좋은 소식이라면 왜 마을에 전화하지 않고 한밤중에 전화를 했나요?
There's another problem.
또 다른 문제가 있습니다.
Soon, a disruptor is going to show up
곧 방해자가 나타날 것입니다
and distance us from Ba Bi. Why?
Ba Bi로부터 우리를 멀어지게 해주세요. 왜?
What? Who is the disruptor?
무엇? 방해자는 누구인가?
My hunch says it's Da Eun!
직감으로는 다은인 것 같아요!
I have a question.
질문이 있습니다.
When did you start liking me?
언제부터 나를 좋아하기 시작했어요?
Hunch cell's ominous hunch
직감세포의 불길한 직감
eventually led to Yumi's question, but ...
결국 유미의 질문으로 이어졌지만...
Huh?
뭐?
- You're so cool. - I don't think it's her.
- 정말 멋지네요. - 내 생각엔 그 사람 아닌 것 같아.
It's not?
그렇지 않습니까?
Look at her! What are you seeing that's making you suspicious?
그녀를보세요! 당신이 보고 있는 것이 무엇을 의심하게 만드는가?
She just ended up saying something unnecessary to Ba Bi for no reason.
결국 그녀는 아무 이유 없이 바비에게 불필요한 말을 하게 됐다.
Is it not Da Eun?
다은아닌가?
- I'm going! - Oh, okay. I'm ...
- 갈게요! - 아, 그래요. 나는 ...
I'm sorry, Reason.
미안해요, 이유.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
- Are you sure this time? - Yes.
- 이번엔 확실해요? - 예.
I'm sure! The disruptor is the Editor-in-Chief!
나는 확신한다! 방해꾼은 편집장이다!
The Editor-in-Chief makes Ba Bi misunderstand.
편집장은 바비를 오해하게 만든다.
You saw earlier too, right? When Ba Bi reacted to the doughnuts.
아까도 봤지? 바비가 도넛에 반응했을 때.
- Could it be? - My hunch is definitely right!
- 그럴 수도 있지? - 내 예감이 확실히 맞았어!
It's Ahn Dae Yong. You have to be wary of Ahn Dae Yong.
안대용입니다. 안대용을 조심해야 한다.
But he's the Editor-in-Chief, what can we do?
그런데 그 사람이 편집장인데 우리가 뭘 할 수 있겠어요?
My Love Muse
내 사랑 뮤즈
It's better.
더 좋습니다.
Yes, it got a lot better.
네, 많이 좋아졌습니다.
Right? I also really enjoyed it, Writer.
오른쪽? 저도 정말 즐거웠어요, 작가님.
- Thank you. - You did great.
- 감사합니다. - 정말 잘했어요.
Oh no, not at all. That's such a relief, really.
아뇨, 전혀요. 정말 다행이에요.
Did you eat lunch late again today?
오늘도 점심을 늦게 먹었나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
No.
아니요.
Then, let's eat dinner together. You've worked hard.
그럼 저녁 같이 먹자. 당신은 열심히 일했습니다.
Yes, ask the Editor-in-Chief to buy us something delicious!
응, 편집장한테 맛있는 거 사달라고 부탁해!
Oh, uh, sure.
아, 어, 물론이죠.
Let's meet on the first floor in ten minutes. Miss Mi Yeon, please bring her with you.
10분 뒤에 1층에서 만나자. 미연씨 꼭 데려오세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Oh right! Editor-in-Chief.
아 맞다! 편집장.
I was really thankful for the doughnuts the other night. I enjoyed them.
어젯밤에 도넛을 주셔서 정말 감사했습니다. 나는 그것을 즐겼다.
Conference Room
회의실
This is it, this is it! This is the strategy of love!
바로 이것이다, 바로 이것이다! 이것이 사랑의 전략이다!
I'll make another step towards her today!
오늘은 그녀를 향해 한걸음 더 나아가겠습니다!
Do you like it?
당신은 그것을 좋아합니까?
It's so good.
너무 좋아요.
Current time 7:55.
현재 시간 7시 55분.
As we're finishing eating, I use a skill.
식사를 마치면서 스킬을 사용합니다.
Could I get another bottle of the same wine?
같은 와인을 한 병 더 주문할 수 있나요?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Nice wine time.
즐거운 와인타임.
A dating technique that extends the meal time by ordering wine at the end of the meal.
식사가 끝나면 와인을 주문해 식사 시간을 연장하는 데이트 기법.
You're ordering another one?
하나 더 주문하시나요?
Aren't you overdoing it?
너무 과하게 하는거 아냐?
Since the writer is enjoying it so much.
작가님이 너무 좋아하시니까.
It's all right.
괜찮아요.
But it is good.
그러나 그것은 좋다.
Please enjoy.
즐겨주세요.
If my calculations are correct, Mi Yeon will leave at 8:10 pm.
내 계산이 맞다면 미연 씨는 오후 8시 10분에 출발할 거예요.
But, what should I do ...
그런데 어떻게 해야 할까요...
I think I have to get going.
내 생각엔 가봐야 할 것 같아.
Nice!
멋진!
Really? Why?
정말? 왜?
It's because Mi Yeon's been married for three months
미연이가 결혼한 지 3개월이 되었기 때문이죠
and her husband leaves work at 8 pm.
그리고 남편은 저녁 8시에 퇴근해요.
You can't. We just ordered another wine. Who's going to finish it?
당신은 할 수 없습니다. 우리는 방금 다른 와인을 주문했습니다. 누가 끝내겠어요?
Let's just finish this and all leave together.
이만 끝내고 모두 함께 떠나자.
I'm sorry. My husband and I are going to see a late-night movie tonight.
죄송합니다. 남편과 저는 오늘 밤 심야 영화를 볼 예정입니다.
Then we can't make you stay.
그러면 우리는 당신을 머물게 할 수 없습니다.
Then let's all leave together now.
그럼 이제 모두 함께 떠나자.
N-no! Shut her mouth!
아뇨! 그 입 다물어!
How about we two finish this then leave?
우리 둘이 이걸 끝내고 떠나는 게 어때?
Since it's getting late.
점점 늦어지니까.
Oh… Sure.
아… 물론이죠.
Someone's coming over there.
누군가 저기로 오고 있어요.
- Who are you? - Yeah, who are you?
- 누구세요? - 응, 당신은 누구죠?
Yo, hi.
요, 안녕.
Stop, stop.
그만해, 그만해.
Do you know the password?
비밀번호를 아시나요?
- I don't. - Y-you don't?
- 나는 아니에요. - 그렇지 않나요?
Then you can't get through.
그러면 통과할 수 없습니다.
If you're cute, you can, but you're not cute.
귀여우면 할 수 있지만 귀엽지는 않습니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
I'm here to open the gate of heart myself. So don't mind me and do your thing.
나는 마음의 문을 직접 열기 위해 여기에 왔습니다. 그러니 내 말은 신경쓰지 말고 네 일을 해라.
You're going to open the gate of heart yourself?
마음의 문을 스스로 열 것인가?
What's he doing?
그 사람 뭐하는 거야?
You must not know that if you relate to a person more than three times,
한 사람과 세 번 이상 관계를 맺으면
the gate of heart opens up.
마음의 문이 열립니다.
You said that you like Writer Lee Dong Geon, right?
이동건 작가를 좋아한다고 했죠?
Yes, I'm a big fan.
네, 저는 열렬한 팬이에요.
Then have you read his new release? It's really good. It's called—
그럼 그의 신작을 읽어보셨나요? 정말 좋아요. 이름은—
- '100% Sweetness'! - 100%
- '달콤함 100%'! - 100%
You have related once.
당신은 한 번 관련이 있습니다.
You enjoyed it too.
당신도 그것을 즐겼습니다.
I really enjoyed it as well.
저도 정말 즐거웠어요.
Writer Lee Dong Geon must be a genius.
이동건 작가는 천재임에 틀림없다.
It gets better every time.
매번 좋아지고 있습니다.
I've met him and he really is a genius.
제가 그 사람을 만났는데 정말 천재예요.
Really?
정말?
Are you close to him?
당신은 그 사람과 가깝나요?
I'm close enough to meet and call him once in a while.
나는 그 사람을 가끔씩 만나서 전화할 만큼 친하다.
That must be great.
정말 좋을 것 같아요.
My wish is to meet him in person one day.
내 소원은 언젠가 그를 직접 만나는 것이다.
Let's meet him together if an opportunity comes up next time.
다음에 기회가 된다면 같이 만나자.
Really? Wow. I'm so excited.
정말? 우와. 정말 신난다.
- What's going on? - One of the latches disappeared!
- 무슨 일이에요? - 걸쇠 중 하나가 사라졌습니다!
All right, shall I loosen the rest of the latches?
좋아요, 나머지 걸쇠도 풀어드릴까요?
This won't do! It must really be Ahn Dae Yong!
이건 안 돼! 정말 안대용이 틀림없어요!
I need to alert the village.
마을에 알려야 해요.
Wait for me!
나를 기다려라!
Should I recommend a few books similar to '100% Sweetness'?
'달콤함 100%' 비슷한 책 몇 권 추천해볼까?
That would be great!
그러면 좋을 것 같아요!
I always upload my recommendations on my social media.
저는 항상 소셜 미디어에 추천 내용을 업로드합니다.
Are you on social media?
소셜 미디어를 사용하고 있나요?
I don't use it very often, but I am on social media.
자주 사용하지는 않지만 소셜 미디어를 사용하고 있습니다.
Just a minute.
잠시만요.
Social media is the best master key to relating with one another.
소셜 미디어는 서로 관계를 맺는 데 가장 좋은 마스터 키입니다.
That's my social media account.
그게 내 소셜 미디어 계정이에요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Relating 34%
관련도 34%
Now, let's find things we can relate to.
이제 우리가 공감할 수 있는 것들을 찾아보자.
Relating in progress.
관련 진행 중입니다.
Hehe. So excited. I love Hawaiian burgers.
헤헤. 너무 신난다. 나는 하와이안 버거를 좋아한다.
We really have a similar tastes.
우리는 정말 취향이 비슷해요.
I only eat Hawaiian burgers too.
저도 하와이안 버거만 먹어요.
Really?
정말?
What are you saying? We prefer bulgogi burgers.
무슨 말을 하는 거야? 우리는 불고기 버거를 더 좋아해요.
Shut up.
입 다물어.
That's not important!
그것은 중요하지 않습니다!
My favorite churros.
내가 제일 좋아하는 츄러스.
Oh my, you like churros, too?
어머, 너도 츄러스 좋아해?
My favorite snack is churros.
제가 가장 좋아하는 간식은 츄러스입니다.
I know the best churros place in Seoul. Should I tell you?
나는 서울에서 가장 맛있는 츄러스 가게를 알고 있어요. 내가 당신에게 말해야 할까요?
Yes!
예!
You've related twice.
당신은 두 번이나 관계를 맺었습니다.
Shall I loosen the last latch?
마지막 걸쇠를 풀어드릴까요?
Where is that churros place?
그 츄러스집이 어디죠?
I'll send you the link for that later.
나중에 해당 링크를 보내드리겠습니다.
Ah, all right.
아, 알았어.
Related with books and food.
책과 음식과 관련이 있습니다.
Let's find the last topic.
마지막 주제를 찾아보겠습니다.
If I didn't close my eyes and open my mouth, this would've been the pic of my life.
만약 내가 눈을 감고 입을 열지 않았다면, 이것은 내 인생의 사진이었을 것이다.
My boyfriend.
내 남자친구.
This must be your boyfriend.
이 사람이 당신 남자친구임에 틀림없어요.
Yes.
예.
That's not really a good picture.
정말 좋은 사진은 아닙니다.
Since your ring was on your right hand, I thought…
반지가 오른손에 있었으니까...
It was too loose on my left finger, so it kept falling off.
왼쪽 손가락이 너무 헐거워서 계속 떨어졌어요.
So I had to wear it here.
그래서 여기서 입어야 했어요.
I see.
알겠어요.
It was indeed a couple ring.
그야말로 커플링이었습니다.
Your boyfriend looks like a celebrity.
당신의 남자친구는 연예인 같아요.
You look good together.
당신은 함께 좋아 보인다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Let's stop it now. She even has a boyfriend.
이제 그만하자. 그녀에게는 남자친구도 있습니다.
In any case, It wasn't meant to be.
어쨌든 그럴 의도는 아니었습니다.
I don't believe in fate anymore.
나는 더 이상 운명을 믿지 않는다.
Right, let's not believe in fate anymore.
그래, 더 이상 운명을 믿지 말자.
Let's not believe in it
믿지 말자
and let's return to being the competent editor-in-chief, Ahn Dae Yong.
그리고 다시 유능한 편집장 안대용으로 돌아가자.
There is no fate.
운명은 없습니다.
There is only choice.
선택의 여지가 있습니다.
Choice?
선택?
Let's initiate plan B starting now.
지금부터 플랜B를 시작해보자.
I really enjoyed dinner, Chief Editor.
편집장님, 저녁 정말 맛있게 먹었습니다.
You've worked so hard. This was nothing.
당신은 정말 열심히 일했습니다. 이것은 아무것도 아니었습니다.
Still, it was really tasty.
그래도 정말 맛있었어요.
- Writer Kim. - Yes?
- 김작가. - 예?
Do you know how I became editor-in-chief of a publishing company when I majored in business?
제가 경영학을 전공하면서 어떻게 출판사 편집장이 되었는지 아시나요?
No.
아니요.
Do you know what was the first literary work I read?
내가 처음으로 읽은 문학 작품이 무엇인지 아시나요?
What are you doing right now?
지금 뭐하세요?
Was your plan B telling her that she was your crush?
당신의 계획 B는 그녀가 당신이 좋아하는 사람이라고 말하고 있었습니까?
You can never!
당신은 결코 할 수 없습니다!
She has someone that she loves.
그녀에게는 사랑하는 사람이 있습니다.
Are you going to be the disrupter? Are you going to make them break up?
당신은 방해자가 될 것인가? 그 사람들을 헤어지게 만들려고요?
What's Dae Yong's full name?
대용의 이름은 무엇입니까?
What are you saying?
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
Tell me! What's Dae Yong's full name?
말해 주세요! 대용의 이름은 무엇입니까?
Ahn Dae Yong.
안대용.
Yes, you punk. Do you get it? ("Ahn Dae Yong" sounds like "andwae - yo" = "you mustn't, it can't be" in polite form)
응, 이 새끼야. 당신은 그것을 이해합니까? ("안대용"은 "andwae - yo" = "너는 안 돼, 그럴 수 없어"처럼 들린다)
You can't do this!
당신은 이것을 할 수 없습니다!
I can't do this. (Ahn Dae Yong)
나는 이것을 할 수 없습니다. (안대용)
Ahn Dae Yong who loves literature and romance
문학과 낭만을 사랑하는 안대용
can't act like this.
이렇게 행동할 수는 없어.
He can't.
그는 할 수 없습니다.
Editor?
편집자?
What was the first literary book that you read?
당신이 처음으로 읽은 문학 작품은 무엇이었나요?
Oh.
오.
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What was it?
그것은 무엇이었나요?
I suddenly can't remember.
갑자기 기억이 안나네요.
Wait!
기다리다!
I don't think it's Ahn Dae Yong.
안대용은 아닌 것 같아요.
Please get home safely, Writer Kim.
김작가님, 무사히 집에 가세요.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
Adiós, Kim Yumi.
안녕, 김유미.
Adiós, my first love.
아디오스, 내 첫사랑.
You are just my precious Writer Kim now.
당신은 이제 나의 소중한 김작가일 뿐입니다.
Kim Yumi
김유미
It's not him.
그 사람이 아닙니다.
He's not a disruptor.
그는 방해자가 아닙니다.
So it wasn't Ahn Dae Yong?
그럼 안대용이 아니었나요?
Then who could it be?
그렇다면 누구일까요?
Don't you think you misunderstood the message?
메시지를 잘못 이해했다고 생각하지 않나요?
No way.
안 돼요.
From now on, don't wake me up unless you are sure.
이제부터 확실하지 않으면 나를 깨우지 마세요.
Reason, I'm sorry.
이유야, 미안해.
Is it really possible I misunderstood the message?
제가 메시지를 잘못 이해한 것이 정말 가능합니까?
Ba Bi!
바비!
Yumi. I'm sorry I couldn't call you yesterday.
유미. 어제 전화를 못해서 미안해요.
I guess you got home really late.
집에 정말 늦게 들어오셨나 봐요.
My coworkers wanted to go for a second round so I couldn't be the first to leave.
동료들이 두 번째 라운드에 가고 싶어해서 내가 먼저 떠날 수 없었습니다.
I see. Did you drink a lot?
알겠어요. 많이 마셨나요?
No. I didn't drink a lot.
아니요. 많이 마시지 않았어요.
- I drank a lot yesterday. - Da Eun suddenly quit.
- 어제 술을 많이 마셨어요. - 다은이가 갑자기 그만뒀어요.
What?
무엇?
Da Eun quit?
다은이 그만뒀어?
Yes, she quit yesterday so we had a team dinner.
네, 어제 그만둬서 팀 저녁을 먹었어요.
Why?
왜?
She said she got a job at a company in Busan. I think her professor recommended her.
부산에 있는 회사에 취직했다고 하더군요. 내 생각엔 그녀의 교수님이 그녀를 추천하신 것 같아요.
Then she's moving to Busan?
그럼 부산으로 이사간다고?
Yes. Her sister lives in Busan, so she's going to stay there.
예. 그녀의 여동생은 부산에 살고 있어서 그곳에 머물 예정입니다.
Really?
정말?
That's good that she even got a job before she graduated.
졸업하기도 전에 취업을 해서 다행이다.
Yes, it's a good thing.
예, 좋은 일입니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
But who did you get wine from?
그런데 와인은 누구한테서 받았나요?
From the editor-in-chief and Mi Yeon.
편집장과 미연입니다.
This time it's wine? That editor-in-chief must be rich.
이번에는 와인인가? 그 편집장은 분명 부자일 거예요.
He said it was for working hard all night.
밤새도록 열심히 일한 덕분이라고 하더군요.
I'm sure he doesn't just have one or two contracted writers.
나는 그에게 계약된 작가가 한두 명만 있는 것은 아닐 것이라고 확신한다.
But giving snacks or wine every time ... He must be a really competent man.
그런데 매번 간식이나 와인을 주는데... 정말 유능한 사람이겠군요.
What? Is Yu Ba Bi jealous?
무엇? 유바비가 질투하는 걸까요?
I'm not jealous.
나는 질투하지 않습니다.
I think you are being jealous.
질투하는 것 같아요.
You were jealous of the doughnuts and wine.
당신은 도넛과 와인을 질투했습니다.
I'm right.
내 말이 맞아.
If I say you're right, are you going to stop eating them?
내가 옳다고 하면 그만 먹을 건가요?
If you admit it, I will.
인정한다면 그럴게요.
I'm jealous.
나는 질투한다.
- Are you happy? - I'm so happy.
- 행복해요? - 정말 기뻐요.
Always be jealous, it's thrilling.
늘 질투하세요. 짜릿해요.
My pervert.
내 변태.
What about your hangover?
숙취는 어떻습니까?
Team Leader!
팀 리더!
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
To work. I left my car there yesterday.
일하다. 어제 거기에 차를 두고 왔어요.
Oh, that's right.
아, 그렇군요.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
- I'm going to meet up with my friend. She wanted to see me before I left. - I see.
- 친구를 만나러 갈 거예요. 그녀는 내가 떠나기 전에 나를 만나고 싶어했습니다. - 알겠어요.
When are you going to Busan?
부산에는 언제 가시나요?
I'm going to have lunch, so sometime in the afternoon.
점심을 먹을 예정이니까 오후쯤에요.
You're leaving right away. Are you flying?
지금 바로 떠나시네요. 당신은 날고 있습니까?
- Yes. - I see.
- 예. - 알겠어요.
Take care of yourself.
몸 조심하세요.
I will.
그럴게요.
Team Leader, thank you for everything.
팀장님, 모든 것에 감사드립니다.
There's nothing to be thankful for. You worked hard.
감사할 것이 하나도 없습니다. 당신은 열심히 일했습니다.
No, I really learned a lot and it was really fun.
아니요, 정말 많이 배웠고 정말 즐거웠습니다.
I'm really thankful.
정말 감사해요.
All right.
괜찮은.
- Well ... - Huh?
- 음 ... - 응?
Actually, I'm someone who falls in love easily.
사실 저는 사랑에 쉽게 빠지는 편이에요.
People like that don't usually confess their feelings.
그런 사람들은 대개 자신의 감정을 고백하지 않습니다.
Because after a few days, the person they like changes.
며칠 지나면 좋아하는 사람이 바뀌거든요.
But recently I started to like someone.
그런데 최근에 나는 누군가를 좋아하기 시작했습니다.
He was a little different.
그는 조금 달랐습니다.
Every day I would only think of him and wanted to know more about him.
매일 나는 그 사람만을 생각했고 그에 대해 더 알고 싶었습니다.
I thought I was someone who falls in love easily.
나는 쉽게 사랑에 빠지는 사람인 줄 알았다.
So it worked out for the better since I got a job first.
그래서 제가 먼저 취업한 이후로 더 잘 됐어요.
- So that's why you are going to Busan?
- 그래서 부산에 가시나요?
Well, partially.
글쎄, 부분적으로.
Why? It's not wrong to like someone.
왜? 누군가를 좋아하는 것은 잘못된 것이 아닙니다.
That's true.
그것은 사실이다.
There's nothing wrong with liking someone
누군가를 좋아하는 것은 잘못된 것이 아니다
but he has a girlfriend.
하지만 그에겐 여자친구가 있어요.
"He won't know what I'm talking about."
"그 사람은 내가 무슨 말을 하는지 모를 거예요."
That's what the kid, Da Eun, thought.
다은이라는 꼬마는 그렇게 생각했다.
It's better not to say anything in this situation, right?
이런 상황에서는 아무 말도 하지 않는 것이 낫겠죠?
This is something you can't pretend you don't understand.
이해하지 못하는 척 할 수 없는 일이다.
Yes, if you don't have to, then it's best not to.
예, 그럴 필요가 없다면 하지 않는 것이 가장 좋습니다.
I think what Da Eun is saying right now is dangerous.
지금 다은이가 하는 말은 위험한 것 같아요.
You're right. What she just said ...
당신 말이 맞아요. 그녀가 방금 말한 내용은 ...
This is an earthquake, right?
이거 지진 맞죠?
It's an earthquake. Everything is shaking.
지진이에요. 모든 것이 흔들리고 있습니다.
It stopped.
그것은 멈췄다.
Love!
사랑!
Reason.
이유.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
What was that earthquake about?
그 지진은 무엇 때문이었나요?
If you ask me about natural phenomena it's difficult for me to say.
자연 현상에 관해 나에게 묻는다면 대답하기가 어렵습니다.
Then whom should I ask?
그럼 누구한테 물어볼까?
It's an earthquake caused by what Da Eun said.
다은이가 한 말 때문에 발생한 지진이에요.
Why is there an earthquake from something that kid said?
그 꼬마가 한 말 때문에 왜 지진이 나는 걸까?
It's because anyone who heard that would be surprised.
그 말을 듣는 사람은 누구나 놀랄 것이기 때문이다.
Right?
오른쪽?
You know that kid is bold.
그 아이가 대담한 거 아시죠?
The bus is coming.
버스가 오고 있어요.
Then have a safe trip.
그럼 안전한 여행 되세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Take care.
잘 지내세요.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
To Hanlim
한림으로
Don't give it too much meaning, it was nothing.
너무 큰 의미를 부여하지 마십시오. 아무것도 아니었습니다.
It was just a little tremor, wasn't it?
그냥 약간의 떨림이었죠, 그렇죠?
It really was nothing.
정말 아무것도 아니었어요.
Sudden Cold Wave Warning
갑작스러운 한파 경보
- I probably packed everything, right? - Yes.
- 아마 다 챙겼을 텐데요, 그렇죠? - 예.
If not, call me if you need anything.
그렇지 않다면 필요한 것이 있으면 나에게 전화하세요.
I'm leaving.
나는 떠난다.
♫ We know ♫
♫ 우리는 알고 있어요 ♫
♫ the hidden things inside ♫
♫ 그 안에 숨겨진 것들 ♫
♫ Pretend you don't know ♫
♫ 모르는 척 ♫
This is crazy!
이건 미친 짓이야!
This is a real earthquake!
이건 진짜 지진이다!
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 합니까?
This isn't a small tremor!
이건 작은 흔들림이 아니예요!
♫ I feel I am changing ♫
♫ 내가 변하고 있는 것 같아요 ♫
♫ For us ♫
♫ 우리를 위해 ♫
♫ now even the small things ♫
♫ 이제 작은 것까지 ♫
You're telling me this is nothing?
이게 아무것도 아니라고 말하는 겁니까?
♫ In my favorite movie ♫
♫ 내가 가장 좋아하는 영화 속에서 ♫
♫ will we be somewhere in that scene? You and I. ♫
♫ 우리는 그 장면 어딘가에 있을까요? 너와 나. ♫
♫ Nightfallin' ♫
♫ 나이트폴링 ♫
♫ At the end of the sun setting ♫
♫ 해가 지는 마지막 순간에 ♫
♫ In me ♫
♫ 내 안에 ♫
♫ I feel you intensifying ♫
♫ 당신이 점점 더 격렬해지는 걸 느껴요 ♫
♫ Sweet cologne Truth be told ♫
♫ 달콤한 향수 사실이야 ♫
♫ You and I ♫
♫ 당신과 나 ♫
♫ we are walking to the same beat ♫
♫ 우리는 같은 박자에 맞춰 걷고 있어요 ♫
♫ Nightfallin' ♫
♫ 나이트폴링 ♫
♫ Because you are within my two eyes ♫
♫ 당신은 내 두 눈 안에 있기 때문이죠 ♫
♫ I'm hiding ♫
♫ 나는 숨어 있어요 ♫
♫ the especially red cheeks ♫
♫ 유난히 빨간 뺨 ♫
♫ Yes I know Truth be told ♫
♫ 네 알아요 진실을 말해주세요 ♫
Yumi's Cells 2 Preview
유미의 세포들 2 미리보기
This is illustrator, Control Ji.
일러스트레이터 Control Ji 입니다.
Not Control Ji, it's Control Z. Z!
컨트롤지가 아니라 컨트롤ZZ입니다!
What did you think of the manuscript?
원고에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
I think the couple that comes out here is too honest with each other.
여기 나오는 커플은 서로에게 너무 솔직한 것 같아요.
Should I say it's not realistic at all?
전혀 현실적이지 않다고 해야 할까요?
You put your place up for sale? Why?
당신의 집을 매물로 내놓았나요? 왜?
I think I should move closer to work.
직장에 더 가까이 가야 할 것 같아요.
That's a shame.
안타깝네요.
Miss Da Eun?
다은씨?
He put his place up for sale.
그는 자신의 집을 매물로 내놓았습니다.
Why? Because of me?
왜? 나 때문에?
What?
무엇?
♫ Wandering this time which is filled by you ♫
♫ 너로 가득찬 이 시간을 헤매며 ♫